

Christian Grail

Software Engineer focused on great user experiences. I'm a full stack developer with experience in Java, Swift, SAP ABAP, C#, and JavaScript. I've developed cloud-native and on-prem apps.

I am more interested in solving problems than about the technology.

ABOUT

Skills:

- Java
- Swift
- Web Development
- React/Angular/SAP UI5
- Cloud-native development
- SAP ABAP
- Architecture
- Node.js
- Big Data Visualization
- AR/VR
- git
- Rapid Prototyping
- Software Development Life Cycle
- Agile Software Engineering
- Unit Tests
- Test Driven Development
- Clean Code
- Enterprise Integration
- TAM Diagrams
- Scrum

List of my talks:

www.grails.de/about

Contact:

<u>christian@grails.de</u> <u>www.linkedin.com/in/cgrail</u>

EXPERIENCE

Development Architect since 2016

SAP Headquarters Germany

- Software development architect for the cloud-native and microservice based payroll system
- Inscribe handwriting and ML based conversational digital assistant for the iPad
- Data Encounter 3D big data exploration tool based on AR/VR
- Speaker at conferences like iOS Conf Singapore, SAP TechEd, JavaLand, JAX, Google DevFest, AngularMix and AppDevCon

Development Architect 2014 - 2016

SAP Labs Silicon Valley

- SAP Build complete set of tools to design and build apps
- Developed web apps like Simple Finance and People Profile
- Speaker at conferences like O'Reilly OSCON and EclipseCon

Senior Developer 2008 - 2014

SAP Headquarters Germany

- Developed tools for the git-based bug fixing and SDLC process
- Developed reference implementations for SAP NW technology
- Led trainings for topics like unit testing, TDD, clean code and JS

Developer 2006 - 2008

InterComponentWare Walldorf, Germany

Java based CRM system for health insurance providers

Education

Computer Science and Economics 2003 – 2006

SRH University Heidelberg - Dipl. Inf. (FH)